(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
PAXTON: I heard Magnum condoms
are basically
the same size
as regular condoms.
BARNES: Mmm-mmm.
PAXTON: Which makes you
think. like.
what else do we believe
just because of marketing?
Like. if you grew up
being told
the Book of Mormon is fake.
you'd probably believe
it was fake 'cause
that's what you were told.
BARNES: No. Magnums are huge.
My sister said her ex-husband
had a scary big peen.
like. frighteningly big.
and they had to wear Magnums.
PAXTON: (SIGHS)
Sounds made up.
- BARNES: Elephant trunk.
- (CROW CAWING)
(CLICKS TONGUE) Yup.
That's what she would call it.
(PAXTON EXHALES)
PAXTON: I was
watching this video.
I'm not sure where I saw it.
It was these two people
having intercourse.
um. sexual intercourse.
sex. and. uh.
and a cameraman filming them.
Like an amateur
porno... nography type thing?
Um. and the girl in the video
was moaning loudly.
as in typical. I assume.
in that kind of video.
Just screaming.
And then. all of a sudden.
off camera. in the hallway.
you hear this lady yell.
through the wall.
"We can hear you!"
And the couple stop sex-ing.
And the look of embarrassment
and horror on their faces
was so painful.
And the porno-girl
who's. like.
taking it from behind-ish.
says something defiant. like.
"Good!" under her breath.
but you can literally
see her soul
being sucked out of her body.
right then and there.
All of her dignity gone.
as if realizing
for the first time. like.
"Wow. this is my life.
"I'm f-ing a stranger
on camera for money."
And I just thought.
"Like. wow.
that is really poignant."
Because. like. in that moment.
I was like. "Yeah."
God's real.
We have souls.
It's divine confirmation.
Do you watch a lot of...
- No! I do not! No.
- (CHUCKLES)
- I do not watch porno-ography.
- Okay. okay.
No.
- It's okay.
- No! I said no!
- I'm not!
- Mmm-hmm. I know.
- Not a pornography watcher.
- Okay. Okay. (LAUGHING)
Oh. I hope this goes well.
(SIGHS)
I know it's not a competition.
but I haven't baptized
a single investigator
on my mission yet. (SNIFFS)
It's okay.
I've only converted.
- like. eight or nine people.
- Eight or nine?
Balls.
Anyway. what do you think
about what I was saying?
The porno thing?
Like...
How has God shown you
that the church is true?
I don't know.
I guess I haven't really...
I haven't really
thought about it.
But you know it's true.
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
PAXTON: If ye receive
no witness
until after the trial
of your faith...
- If ye receive no witness...
- (PANTING)
BARNES: Who do we have...
after this couple again?
PAXTON: I think we have
the bald guy we met at Costco.
BARNES: Okay. Oh. yeah.
PAXTON: Okay. for every flight
of stairs...
BARNES: Yeah?
PAXTON: ...our husband
- gets five times hotter.
- (BARNES LAUGHS)
Hi. good afternoon. ma'am.
My name is Sister Barnes.
and this is my companion.
Sister Paxton.
Are you interested in learning
about our savior.
Jesus Christ?
(SIGHS WEARILY) Okay.
- Hi!
- Good afternoon.
- Hi. are you interest...
- My name is. uh.
Sister Barnes. and...
PAXTON: You ever feel
like when you sing.
it's. like.
too high or too low?
BARNES: I don't really
like to sing.
PAXTON: I think you have
a beautiful voice.
I know I don't have
a beautiful voice. but...
BARNES: No. you do. You do.
PAXTON: I enjoy it.
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
Oh. my gosh.
I already love these girls.
SORORITY GIRL: Hey...
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
- (CAR HONKS)
- (GIRLS SCREAM)
SORORITY GIRL: Sorry!
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
Sorry! Can we get a pic?
Oh. of course!
Uh. here.
- Is it true?
- Is what true?
- Do you wear magic underwear?
- What?
- (PAXTON GASPS)
- (CAR HONKS)
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
Oh. my gosh!
Come on. let's go.
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
(BICYCLE SPOKES CLACKING)
- (WIND WHISTLING)
- (PAXTON SOBBING)
(SNIFFLES)
(EXHALES)
This is it.
(SOFT INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
PAXTON:
People think we're weird.
What do you mean?
I don't know.
That South Park musical
kind of makes fun of us.
I listened
to some of the songs.
and they're actually
pretty funny.
(LOCK CLICKS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Anyway. who...
who cares what people think?
You're awesome.
Thanks.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(RAIN PATTERING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
PAXTON: (WHISPERING)
Hi. I'm Sister Paxton. Hi.
Hello. I'm Sister Paxton.
This is my companion.
Sister Barnes.
God chooses prophets.
- such as Adam.
- (THUNDER RUMBLING)
Noah. Abraham and Moses.
The prophets teach about God
and receive revelation.
All right.
Let's get you a baptism.
(CHUCKLES)
Okay.
(THUD)
(FLOORBOARD CREAKING)
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(LOCK CLICKS)
Ah!
Good afternoon.
- Hi. (CHUCKLES)
- Good afternoon.
- Hi.
I'm Sister Paxton. and this is
my companion. Sister Barnes.
Um. are you Mr. Reed?
I am. Hello to you.
- Hello. Wait.
- Hi.
You are Paxton.
you are Barnes.
- Barnes?
- Um. no. I'm...
- Paxton. Barnes.
- Barnes. yes.
- BARNES: Yeah.
Mr. Reed. it's so nice
to meet you. finally.
We were just in the area.
and we wanted to stop by
because you mentioned
you might be interested
in learning more about
the Church of Jesus Christ
of Latter-day Saints?
Yeah! Yeah. yeah. yeah.
(PAXTON AND BARNES CHUCKLE)
Mr. Reed. we would like
to give you this booklet.
as it will help you
understand the restoration.
I... I actually
have one already.
but. um. you can never
have too many.
It... it tells you
all the ways
the Heavenly Father
can reveal His gospel.
- As a part of His plan...
- Thank you.
...God chooses prophets.
such as Adam. Noah. Abraham
and Moses.
- Uh. prophets...
- Yeah. well. talking of Noah...
(CHUCKLING) ...it is very.
very wet.
...teach about God
and receive revelation.
and they interpret
the word of God. and preach
the gospel to the world.
and because of Apostasy...
Would you like to come inside?
...people lose knowledge
of the gospel.
Do you have a girl roommate?
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
A girl. who?
BARNES: A... a roommate?
We can't come inside unless
another woman is present
but. um. we can. uh.
stay out here
in the doorway.
if that's fine with you?
It's just for safety.
We don't mind the rain.
Well. my wife is home.
Does that count?
- Yeah!
- Perfect.
When you said "roommate."
I panicked. I...
I haven't had a roommate
since. uh...
Anyway. I... I have a soulmate
and that is good enough?
- Yes!
- That's great!
We'd love to come in
and meet your wife.
Then come on in!
Great!
- Do you like pie?
- Yeah!
MR. REED: My wife has pie
in the oven.
I've gained so much weight
on my mission.
People are always
feeding us treats.
We never seem
to turn them down. (CHUCKLES)
Well. my wife loves to bake.
(PAXTON AND BARNES CHUCKLE)
- May I take your coats?
- BARNES: Oh. yes.
(SIGHS) I really love pie.
I'm super excited.
My grandma used to make
the best pie.
Okay. well. you and my wife
are gonna get on very well.
- Great.
- Oh. one thing.
the walls and ceilings
have metal in them.
- I hope that's okay.
- We don't mind.
Good!
Well. I will go
and check on the snacks.
Make yourselves at home.
Thank you.
(DOOR CREAKING)
(CLOCK TICKING)
(VELCRO TEARS)
(GLASS CASE SHUTS)
(SOFT CHUCKLE)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(CLOCK TICKING)
(RAIN PATTERING)
(WINGS FLUTTERING)
- (GLASS CLINKING)
- (WINGS FLUTTERING)
(FLOOR CREAKS)
- (THUD)
- (MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(SIGHS)
(ICE CUBES CLINKING
IN GLASSES)
MR. REED:
My wife is being shy.
(PAXTON CHUCKLES)
But the pie. the pie is nigh.
(LAUGHING)
She'll have to be in the room
with us too.
Yes. of course! Of course.
right. I understand.
Please take a seat.
take a seat. take a seat.
Couple of colas.
Help... help yourself.
I think...
it is good to be religious.
Well. our work here is done.
(CHUCKLES) No. I just want you
to know that before we start.
Yeah. I think
that we would consider
that refreshing to hear.
Well. sometimes. it feels like
maybe religion isn't at
the center of culture anymore.
Well. it's fading. isn't it?
Yeah. over time. Mm-hmm.
Okay. are you ready
to hear about
our Heavenly Father's
plan for you?
I am! Wait.
Where are you both from?
Me? Ogden. Utah.
One of eight daughters.
I know.
- it's as bad as it sounds.
- (ALL CHUCKLE)
And Sister Barnes
is from Salt Lake City.
Uh. Philadelphia. originally.
MR. REED: Ah.
And you're both
raised in the church. yeah?
Born and raised.
My mother was a convert.
so. um.
when my dad passed away.
we auditioned
a few different churches.
just to see what was out there
and see if we still
believed in it.
MR. REED:
I know that feeling.
I know that feeling very well.
It's so important
to find your faith
in a doctrine
you actually believe.
and that's a very.
very personal struggle.
That is a personal challenge
that I have struggled with
for a very. very long time.
You know.
what is the one.
true religion? (CHUCKLES)
PAXTON: It's funny.
Sister Hall was telling us
that we should
prioritize other
investigators. (CHUCKLES)
- Oh. (LAUGHS)
- Oh. but no! I...
- (BARNES LAUGHING)
- I'm just saying
that I could tell that you
are a very spiritually
curious person.
just like Joseph Smith.
You know. Joseph investigated
many different denominations.
Presbyterian. Methodist.
Catholicism.
And none of them quite fit.
which is why
Joseph founded our church.
BARNES: Mm-hmm.
As I understand it.
stop me when I go wrong.
he was visited in the night
by an angel called Morony.
PAXTON: Moroni.
BARNES: Moroni. Yeah.
Moroni. who showed him
where he could locate
some golden plates
near his home.
His mysterious translation
of those plates
form the basis of this.
- (LOUD THUD)
- (PAXTON AND BARNES LAUGH)
PAXTON: Wow!
No. you read more than we do!
- (MR. REED CHUCKLES)
- No. seriously.
we should be more like you.
Mr. Reed!
(CHUCKLES) Mr. "Read."
(LAUGHING)
The pie smells amazing.
And now that you've been
studying The Book of Mormon.
how does it make you feel?
Can you guess
what kind of pie she's making?
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Is it...
blueberry pie?
MR. REED: It is blueberry pie!
- PAXTON: Yes! I knew it!
- (CHUCKLES)
- My favorite!
- (ALL CHUCKLING)
Going back. can I ask
how did your father pass away?
- Um...
- MR. REED: I'm sorry.
- I shouldn't...
- Lou Gehrig's disease.
Blueberry disease?
(CHUCKLING) Okay. that's...
That's... that's wonderful.
blueberry disease.
Who wouldn't want that? Yeah.
PAXTON: Uh...
Lou Gehrig's disease.
- Gehrig's.
- (GASPS)
Oh. that's... that's awful.
I'm so sorry.
I... I... I misheard.
That is a malicious
affliction.
I... I thought
you were making a joke
about the pie. I'm sorry.
Yeah.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Have you seen any signs of
your father since he passed?
Has he tried to communicate
from the other side?
Mmm. no.
Strange.
Well. I'm...
I'm really sorry.
and I'm sorry about the...
- blueberry mix-up.
- (BARNES CHUCKLES)
It's okay. (CHUCKLES)
When I die. I want to come
back as a butterfly.
just to follow around
the people I love.
I'll land right on their hand.
Not their arm. not their...
their head.
right on their fingertip.
so they know it's me.
- (RAPID TICKING)
- MR. REED: Ah.
- BARNES: That's sweet.
- (LIGHTS CLICK)
- (AUDIBLE VOLTAGE DROP)
- (METALLIC CLANK)
- (INHALES SHARPLY)
- PAXTON: Oh!
MR. REED: Apologies!
That is a foible of the house.
(BARNES AND MR. REED CHUCKLE)
I'm sorry. It does that.
It does that.
Um. well...
Ladies. I can't see you now.
- Um. I think it is time.
- Hmm.
BARNES: Time for what?
Time for pie!
(SHOUTS) Pie!
- (MR. REED LAUGHING)
- PAXTON: Woohoo!
MR. REED: And. uh.
time for enlightenment.
- (MR. REED CLAPS)
- BARNES: Oh?
(PAXTON LAUGHS)
MR. REED: I'm sorry. I should
have offered you water.
The word of wisdom forbids
caffeine and alcohol.
doesn't it?
Well. it doesn't. uh.
specifically mention soda.
Sure. it may be healthier
to avoid caffeinated drinks.
but we're just not thirsty.
MR. REED: Aha.
How do you feel
about awkward questions?
The meme?
Heh. no. I want to ask
an awkward. uh.
an icky question.
an insensitive question
that I think
will add depth
to our conversation
very quickly
before the sun goes down
and we're done
for the evening.
But only if you're comfortable
with that.
BARNES: Well. we won't know
if we're comfortable
- until you ask. so...
- Fair point.
BARNES:
Maybe you just ask?
Okay. (CLICKS TONGUE)
If you don't ask.
I'm gonna leave here wondering
what we missed out on.
Very well.
My question is this. Um...
(SIGHS)
Now I feel it's been
built up to. Uh...
(PAXTON CHUCKLES)
Should I request a drum roll?
I'm going to request
a drum roll.
A drum roll please. ladies!
- (PAXTON HUMS)
- (MR. REED LAUGHS)
MR. REED: Keep going!
Keep going! Keep going!
More! More! More!
(PAXTON LAUGHING)
Now. I... I... I...
my question is.
how do you feel
about polygamy?
How do you... how do you feel
about the concept of
a man having multiple wives?
I mean. it's...
it's not for me. um...
BARNES: Are you asking
from a biblical perspective?
MR. REED: Uh. Mormonism
has a controversial history
with the misogynist practice
of men claiming
multiple wives.
But I am fascinated by
the idea of Modern Revelation.
which was used
to erase this behavior
from the church in 1890.
I just think
that's worthy of conversation.
Yeah? Uh...
And what I mean by that
is that we're discussing
a church that
decided that
a controversial practice
was a stain on its reputation.
and an actual hindrance
to recruiting new members.
and so it used revelation.
word of God
told unto the prophet
to banish a provocative
religious pillar
that seemed unsavory
in contemporary times.
Yeah. I know that. um.
it may be difficult
to understand. um.
but. uh. polygamy
was a spiritual mission
needed at the time in order
to grow the ranks
of our membership
in the wake of much hardship
and bloodshed.
Um...
a man having plural wives
meant more... more babies
to help the community grow.
Hmm.
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
It's. yeah.
it's sketch for sure.
- to our modern brains.
- BARNES: And it was...
it was removed from the church
not just because
it was grotesque
or controversial.
but just because
it wasn't necessary anymore.
You see. I worry. and...
forgive my loud language.
uh. (CHUCKLES)
I worry that Joseph Smith
used the concept of polygamy
to legitimize his affairs
with other women.
I worry that Joseph's wife.
Emma Smith.
was upset when he slept
with Fanny Alger.
their sixteen-year-old maid.
I worry that
he formulated a plan
to use revelation
for consequence-free sex
in the aftermath
of that indiscretion
and others like it.
You know. "With great power
comes great responsibility."
Spiderman.
Voltaire.
Right.
MR. REED: I guess what I would
pose to the room is my concern
that polygamy has no
spiritual bearing whatsoever.
That is somewhat
of a distortion. I think...
The church's own history
corroborates
and implies this...
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
...cynical
brainwashing tactic.
Is that true?
I... I... I'm sorry.
I... I'm not sure
where you're getting this.
If revelation by God
is filtered through man
and man is flawed
and man sins and man lies.
then how do we know
any of it's true?
We know it's true because
of how it makes us feel.
Bingo! (CHUCKLES)
That's exactly right!
That's exactly right.
Couldn't agree more.
It's our personal relationship
with God which matters.
Let us talk with our bishop
about some of the points
you're raising. Um...
Question. What's your
favorite fast food?
I try not to eat it.
None of us do. but go on.
we've all got one.
BARNES: Um...
Okay. Burger King is better
than Carl's Junior...
What's Carl's Junior?
Hardee's on the East Coast.
Burger King is better
than Hardee's
which is better
than Rally's...
- Rally's?
- Checkers.
- (MR. REED CHUCKLES)
- Burger King is better
than Hardee's.
which is better than Checkers.
which is better than Wendy's.
which is better than In-N-Out.
which is better
than McDonalds.
than Jack in the Box.
which is better than nothing.
Jack in the Box serves
breakfast all day.
- I love breakfast!
- (MR. REED CHUCKLES)
What about Taco Bell?
We don't talk about Taco Bell.
Why don't we talk
about Taco Bell?
We'd have to talk about
Taco Bell to talk about...
(CHUCKLES) why we don't
talk about Taco Bell.
All right. so...
so Burger King is number one.
- I think it's trash.
- Oh.
MR. REED: Right.
Not Jack in the Box.
I vote Wendy's.
I could support.
Good! Wendy's it is. Yeah.
Do you know?
I've never had a Wendy.
(CHUCKLES)
That came out wrong.
- (BARNES AND PAXTON CHUCKLE)
- It's okay.
MR. REED: So when I started
studying theology.
the last thing
I wanted to do was find...
the Wendy's of religions.
I was just writing
a research paper
for a college class. and I was
content with dabbling.
So. some McNuggets here.
BK Whopper over there.
whatever fit the mood.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
As I studied the genres.
McD. BK. In-N-Out.
i.e.. Mormonism. Scientology.
Islam. Buddhism.
as I got closer to God
through genre
and rigorous study.
as I worked
on my personal relationship
with Heavenly Father.
and I think strengthened it.
do you know what I found?
The more you know.
the less you know.
(CANDLE SIZZLING OUT)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
And by the time I was 50.
I was malnourished
from the fast food of religion
I'd been packing into my brain
for the best part of a decade.
Every sect. cult.
creed. denomination
all claimed to be the one.
true doctrine.
and yet none seemed true when
held under the microscope.
So I wondered
what else was out there.
I promise you.
the last thing I wanted to do
was find
the one true religion.
But unfortunately. I did.
(UNSETTLING MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
Can we meet your wife?
Please?
MR. REED: Of course. yes!
(CHUCKLES)
She just has to be present.
and we want
- to meet her as well.
- BARNES: Yeah.
Sorry. I'll... I'll go ask.
(TIMER WINDING)
(DOOR CREAKS)
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(LIGHT BUZZING)
(CLOCK TICKING)
PAXTON: Sister Barnes.
I don't... I don't know.
Yeah.
I don't want to spook him.
but we should wrap this.
Any messages?
- Nothing.
- (EXHALES)
Okay. Um...
let's just politely wrap this
and head back.
PAXTON:
Just the highlights...
(CRACKLING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(SCRAPING)
(GASPS)
(CLOCK TICKING)
- (OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CLOCK TICKING INTENSIFIES)
- (DOOR OPENS)
- (MUSIC AND TICKING STOPS)
MR. REED:
And she is finally ready.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(CHUCKLES) Sorry about that.
(EXHALES) Come on through.
She's eager to... meet you.
There we are.
- This way.
- Okay.
(GLASSES CLINKING)
One moment. Mr. Reed.
Uh. we're just getting a call
from the Relief Society
president.
- We'll be right there.
- Oh. do you need a minute?
Hi.
- This is Sister Barnes. Um...
- I'll wait.
- I'll wait on the other side.
- Yeah. Just one moment.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
(DOOR CREAKS. SHUTS)
- (SOFTLY) Should we leave?
- (SOFTLY) Now?
- (SOFTLY) Yeah?
- (SOFTLY) Yes? Yes.
(EXHALES)
- (FLOOR CREAKING)
- (TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(TENSE MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
What is it?
Our bikes.
Yeah?
They're locked outside.
So what?
He has our coats.
The key to the bike lock
is in my coat pocket.
So we need our coats.
Yeah.
- We do.
- I don't know. do we?
Walk back
without coats and bikes?
What is that. two miles?
No. I think it's four.
It's a little over the top.
but I...
I'm fine.
I'm fine to walk. yeah?
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
- It's stuck.
- Unlock it.
(TENSE MUSIC BUILDS)
(WHISPERS) There's no... lock.
BARNES: (WHISPERING)
What? Pull harder.
Here. Here.
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
BARNES: All right.
(RATTLING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(PAXTON BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BARNES GRUNTING)
- (CREAKING)
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- (SHUSHES)
- (MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
(DISTANT FOOTSTEPS)
(PAXTON SHUDDERS)
BARNES: (WHISPERING)
Is he still there?
PAXTON: (WHISPERING)
Didn't we hear him leave?
BARNES: Are you sure?
Should we ask him for help?
No.
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Can you fit through this?
- PAXTON: You crazy?
- (SIGHS)
(WIND BLOWING)
Um. we should try Sister Hall. okay?
Or Elder Kennedy. just so
they know where we are.
- (BARNES SIGHS HEAVILY)
- (PHONE BEEPS)
(LINE RINGING)
- (WIND GUSTING)
- (OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(LINE BEEPING)
(SIGHS)
It's not going through.
It's the storm.
Keep trying. okay?
(PHONE BEEPS)
- (BREATH TREMBLES)
- (LINE RINGING)
- (DOORKNOB RATTLING)
- (GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(WIND GUSTING)
- (DOORKNOB RATTLES)
- (PANTING)
- (TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
- (BREATH TREMBLING)
(EXHALES)
Okay.
We ask for help. hmm?
It'll be fine.
(OMINOUS CREAKING)
(RAPID TICKING)
- (LIGHTS CLICK)
- (GASPS)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(TIMER WINDING)
(CRANKING)
(FLOOR CREAKING LIGHTLY)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
(FLOOR CREAKING)
(BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY)
PAXTON: Mr. Reed?
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
(SIGHS. CHUCKLES)
(DOOR LOCK CLICKS)
(JUST LIKE A BUTTERFLY THAT'S
CAUGHT IN THE RAIN PLAYING)
(DOOR CREAKS)
And there they are! Welcome.
Mr. Reed. you have been
too generous with your time.
Sister Paxton and I
were just saying
what a pleasure it's been.
Um. but we just got off
the phone with Sister Hall.
and she needs us
to return to the church.
- MR. REED: Oh! Oh. well...
- Unfortunately. yeah.
I won't keep you
if you wish to leave.
We've been summoned back.
Yeah.
Damn it! Damn it.
'cause we were just
getting started. weren't we?
You know. you had me thinking
that maybe you were
onto something
with your visit. (CHUCKLES)
I've been impressed.
but I understand.
Uh. yeah. your coats are here.
hanging on the back
of the pew.
Excuse me one moment.
Yeah.
(JUST LIKE A BUTTERFLY THAT'S
CAUGHT IN THE RAIN PLAYING)
(THUD)
(WATER SPLASHING)
(MOUTHING) Key.
So... so we just. uh.
need your help
with the door. Um...
It's... it's a little tricky.
I'm sorry?
PAXTON: I think your door is
a bit stuck out there.
The door won't open.
PAXTON:
The front door.
Yeah. the front door
won't open again.
It opened when we came in.
- (CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
- MR. REED: Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
Maybe if you unlock it.
it will open?
No. no. I... I... I understand
what you're asking me.
but. uh.
the deadbolts are on a timer.
I got carried away
with our conversation.
I didn't realize the brace
had been set.
I should have pulled the pin
when you came in.
but I forgot.
So if you are now
regrettably ready to leave.
you'll have to exit
through the back of my house.
Uh. where?
Just through here.
Well. can you just unlock
the front one. please?
We would like to go that way.
Just so we don't
get turned around
and confused
when we get outside.
Yeah. it won't open again
'til morning.
(MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
Please. sir?
MR. REED: Oh. I'm sorry.
I promise you.
it's safe to leave this way.
Huh?
It's a little unusual
to have a door
that. um. locks on a timer?
MR. REED: Uh...
Yes. well. I see that.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah.
And it's...
Well. it's a little unusual
that it can't be unlocked.
MR. REED: No.
I... I... I know.
I am self-aware enough to know
how this might look.
Older man. two young women
in his house.
but I assure you.
you are welcome to leave
through... through the back.
You saw my house
from the outside. right?
BARNES: Mm-hmm.
MR. REED: Right!
So. you know
it's a tiny footprint.
The back of the house
is just there.
(INHALES) Yeah.
Anyway. I will leave you space
to make your decision freely.
Yeah.
To clarify. I am trying...
have been trying very hard
to make it a point
not to pressure you.
so you shouldn't even
feel the need
to fabricate a story
about someone from your ward
calling you to leave.
It's... perfectly fine.
Leave when you want.
It wasn't an excuse.
they do need us back.
No. I know. but you're saying
you took a call
with someone from your ward.
Yeah. a moment ago.
But when you came inside.
I asked if you were okay
with the metal in the walls
and ceilings.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
What do you mean?
I mean that the metal
obstructs cell phone signals.
so I do know
you didn't take a call. But...
(CHUCKLES) Just to be clear.
so you're comfortable.
it is totally fine for you
to leave on your own accord.
You never need to feel like
you have to... (SIGHS)
...make excuses or...
or tell me little...
little... little white lies.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
So which door
takes us outside?
MR. REED: Pff.
Well... (CHUCKLES)
do you have a preference?
Wh... why would I
have a preference?
PAXTON: Should we have
a preference?
That is a fair question.
Not to be completely weird.
but can your wife
please just step in the room.
say hello and walk us
to the back of the house?
I'm not trying to be silly.
I promise. I'm really not.
but there are rules we follow.
and we were upfront with them.
I will ask.
Can I ask you
a question first?
(TENSE MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
Do you...
still believe that my wife
is in the next room?
Despite all the evidence
to the contrary.
the scented candle.
the absence of an oven
with blueberry pie?
Or have you been politely
indulging a lie?
If you still believe that
she's in there. I'll go ask.
but it's something
I want you to think about
and maybe think about
in the context
of your beliefs.
(FOOTSTEPS)
Do you believe in God because
somebody told you
at an impressionable age
that God is real.
despite having doubts
as you got older. despite...
seeing evidence to
the contrary your whole lives?
When your father
lost control of his body.
did you think it was
God's plan to ruin his life?
Or did you go on
believing something
that you know is not true
just to give you comfort
because you were afraid
of what it might mean
if it was all a lie?
I put the scented candle
on the table
because I wanted you to think
about the things
that you believe
just because somebody
asked you to believe them.
Can...
Can we use your phone?
Please?
I... I don't have a telephone.
You have a really
beautiful home. Mr. Reed.
It's like a church in here.
Did you build it yourself?
My wife built it.
- (WATER POURING)
- (CLACK)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
We're gonna leave
through the back
of your house.
Now. is that okay?
MR. REED: Of course.
BARNES: Just like you said.
it's okay.
and we can leave. right?
MR. REED: That's right.
(TENSE MUSIC BUILDS)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
What is it?
(OMINOUS MUSIC RISES)
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- (MUSIC FADES OUT)
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
- Sister Barnes?
(DOOR CREAKING)
That's a basement.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
It doesn't look like
this goes outside.
(WIND GUSTING)
(SLOW. SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC
PLAYING)
(WIND GUSTING)
(TREE BRANCHES CREAKING)
(BUCKET RATTLING)
(SIGHS)
(WATER RUNNING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(WIND HOWLING)
I think that you can
tell that we're regrettably
uncomfortable with this
situation here tonight.
(CLICK)
I'm sorry. but didn't you just
say a moment ago
that you saw the outside
of my house?
- So then you clearly saw...
- (DOOR CREAKING)
...that the back of my house
overhangs a hill.
so you would know
that you have to go down...
(SHUDDERS)
...in order to go out.
(CHUCKLING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
BARNES: I think
it would be best for you
and for all of us
if you could help us
go home because
the Stake President.
he knows where we are.
And the Ward
Missionaries know.
And they'll be expecting us.
And there were witnesses.
weren't there. Sister Barnes?
On our way here.
we passed a police officer?
MR. REED: Whoa! The police?
(CHUCKLES) I promise you.
you're getting way. way. way.
way too worked up.
BARNES: Right.
But I think that we're scared
because you lied
to us earlier.
Do you want me to help?
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
You asked me earlier
if you should
have a preference
between the doors.
I think you should.
I think it's something
you should consider
very carefully.
and then make
the right decision.
Do you want me to help you?
BARNES: Yes.
MR. REED: Okay.
Then. please...
come and stand here.
Both of you come.
Just here.
That's it.
- It's a simple choice.
- (DOOR CREAKING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
But it should not
be made simply.
(TENSE MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
I need you to reflect
very. very deeply
and then make
a sincere decision.
(TENSE MUSIC BUILDS)
(MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
Have you ever played
the Parker Brothers game.
Monopoly?
Monopoly is currently
published in 47 languages.
They sell it
in over 114 countries.
(STATIC)
(THE AIR THAT I BREATHE
BY THE HOLLIES PLAYING)
♪ If I could make a wish ♪
They say over a billion people
have played Monopoly.
But I'm guessing that only
a fraction of that billion
have actually finished it.
Maybe that reminds you
of something else?
Just a thought.
This is what most people mean
when they hear "Monopoly."
There's the pewter avatars.
Everyone has their favorite.
I shall not tell you mine.
Meow!
There's the pastel money
in various denominations.
and. of course. the jail.
Now. this next part
is very important.
Have you ever played
the 1904 board game called
The Landlord's Game?
It is very nearly identical
to Monopoly
in every fundamental way.
There's the jail.
There's free parking.
There's fines and fees.
There's penalties.
for landing
on other people's properties.
and the ultimate goal
of forming monopolies
to force your opponent
out of the game.
What do games have to do
with us leaving?
Everything.
The Landlord's Game
was designed by
American feminist
Elizabeth Magie.
almost three decades before
a heater salesman
from Philadelphia.
Sister Barnes.
changed the name to Monopoly
and sold the concept
as his own
to Parker Brothers in 1935.
This chap was called
Charles Darrow.
went on to become the first
millionaire games designer
in the history of the world.
while poor old Elizabeth Magie
died without ever
being credited for the impact
she had on American culture.
(RECORD SCRATCHES)
(THE AIR THAT I BREATHE
FADES OUT)
I'm talking to you
about iterations.
I need you to have a very
basic understanding
of iterating.
because I'm going to make
a very disturbing
claim tonight.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
It will make your stomachs
sink a little
and your hearts beat faster.
It will make you sick.
It may even...
I'm very sorry...
make you want to...
to die.
(FOOTSTEPS)
(STATIC)
(THE AIR THAT I BREATHE
BY THE HOLLIES PLAYING)
Have you heard
this song before?
You just played it.
No. I mean before tonight.
PAXTON: Mmm-mmm.
I disagree!
I think you've heard it
many. many times before.
but we will come back to that.
You are. are you not. monotheistic?
We believe in Heavenly Father. yes.
MR. REED: Okay.
There are three major
monotheistic religions.
Judaism. Christianity
and Islam.
I call them. "The Big Three."
Judaism. i.e.
"The Original Edition."
Christianity. i.e.
"The Most Popular Edition."
and Islam. "The Newer.
"Second Most Popular Edition."
May I see your Book of Mormon. please?
I'll give it back.
Thank you.
And finally. after 800 years.
this!
Mormonism. i.e.
"The zany regional
spin-off edition."
These are all iterations
of the same source material.
These texts share
many of the same characters
and histories albeit presented
with different meanings
and perspectives.
So no.
I will not accept... (CHUCKLES)
...that you stand there
and tell me
that you've never heard
The Air That I Breathe
by The Hollies.
when I know that you have
heard Creep by Radiohead.
Oh. yes. you have. Come on.
(SINGING)
♪ But I'm a creep! ♪
Yeah?
♪ I'm a weirdo ♪
(LAUGHING)
Okay! "What the hell
am I doing here?"
(MR. REED LAUGHING)
I know these are things
you are thinking right now.
but they're also lyrics
you recognize. yes?
Yes?
The Hollies filed a plagiarism
lawsuit against Radiohead.
which they later settled
by proving
that the melody and rhythm
of The Air That I Breathe
appear in Creep.
How old are you? 19 or 20?
- Something like that. Okay.
- BARNES: Hmm.
So maybe you know
Lana Del Rey.
who remarkably was sued
by Radiohead
for plagiarizing Creep
in her 2017 song
Get Free.
Iterations.
Over time.
Diluting the message.
Obscuring the original.
Judaism is the OG
monotheistic religion.
It should. by a wide margin.
have the most number of
practicing members. And yet.
it makes up only 0.2%
of the world's population.
Why is that?
Why is the original
less popular
than the iteration?
Is it any less true
than the others?
Are we talking about religion
or board games or music?
MR. REED: Yes.
It has the fewest members
because it doesn't advertise.
It doesn't have
people like you.
knocking on doors.
selling people a better life.
a better board game.
a better song.
You ever think about that?
How missionaries
are really just salespeople
for an organization?
The product you're selling
is an idea.
You knock on my door
and you sell.
maybe I buy.
maybe I don't buy.
Those are the rules
of engagement
when I invite you
into my house.
We are negotiating
a transaction of ideologies.
(GASPS)
MR. REED: And what I'm trying
to say to you tonight
is that I have an idea which
I would like to sell to you.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(THE AIR THAT I BREATHE
PLAYS LOUDER)
STOPS PLAYING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(PROJECTOR CRANKS)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- (WIND BLOWING)
- (PAPERS RUSTLING)
MR. REED: My argument
is that the holy texts
which we revere
are just mythological
iterations of stories
which ancient people have been
telling each other
for centuries.
- (CRANKS)
- (WHIRRING)
They're not true or real
in any literal sense.
They are merely a conduit
to a more ancient truth.
(KNOCKING ON WINDOW)
The story of a savior...
who was born to a virgin.
who could perform miracles
and was supernaturally
resurrected.
was a very popular story
for at least a thousand years
before Jesus was born.
- (CLANK)
- One of them has blonde hair.
one of them's brunette.
both dressed similar.
No. Never stopped by.
(CLINK)
MR. REED: Mithras
performed miracles.
He was marked
by the sign of the cross.
Horus. walked on water.
was crucified.
had 12 disciples.
Krishna. he was a carpenter.
born to a virgin.
baptized in a river.
rose from the dead
and ascended into heaven.
This little gallery
depicts 12 gods
who were born
on December the 25th.
all of whom predate
the existence of Jesus.
I am sorry.
but it is impossible
to ignore the influence
of one narrative upon another.
or to ignore the fact
that all these stories
iterate into...
Star Wars: Episode I -
The Phantom Menace.
Can you imagine
thousands of years from now
people accepting Jar Jar
as a significant
religious figure?
Beg your pardon?
MR. REED:
Jar Jar. Jar Jar Binks.
(IMITATING JAR JAR)
Jar Jar! Ex-squeeze me.
(IN NORMAL VOICE) Never mind.
(LIGHTS CLICKING AND BUZZING)
It is all terrifying.
isn't it? I'm sorry.
It is.
It is all...
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Scary.
I'm scared.
I'm scared just saying it
out loud. really.
(OBJECT THUDS)
If God is real. and he watches
when we masturbate.
and he has such a fragile ego
that he only helps us
when we beg him
and shower him with praise.
and he hates gay people
for being what
he made them to be.
well. that's terrifying.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
If there's no God
and we're just horny.
microscopic ants
floating on a rock
through space
with no divine purpose
and no hope
to achieve eternal life.
well...
that's terrifying too.
(FOOTSTEPS)
"Either the church is true
or it is a fraud."
"It is the church
and kingdom of God.
"or it is nothing."
Do you agree with that?
Would it help if I told you
this is Gordon B. Hinckley.
the 15th President
of your church.
- Do you agree with Gordon?
- Yes.
BARNES: Mm-hmm.
MR. REED: Thought you might.
So either it is all true
or none of it's true. yes?
PAXTON: Yes.
BARNES: Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Then I want you
to choose which door
to go through
based on your faith.
Are...
are you asking us
for us to deliberate
our belief in the church?
Is that a factor
which will correspond
to us going home?
MR. REED: I'm asking you
to choose between belief
and disbelief.
My own claim is that all
10.000 verifiable religions
that exist in the world today
are as artificial
as the symbolic church
you are currently standing in.
It is farce.
There is nothing holy here.
Your religious text
is mere ornament...
(THUD)
...as hollow
and as capitalistic
as these ridiculous games.
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(PAXTON BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
(PAPERS RUSTLING)
(BARNES EXHALES)
I want to know
what is going to happen to us
- before we choose.
- I don't even know
how to begin
to answer that question
if it hasn't happened yet.
Wow. Mr. Reed.
you've introduced
a lot of interesting points.
I think we can admit
that you're a very smart man
and we still have
a lot to learn.
So with that.
I would like to agree
that you've...
convinced us.
and we'd like to leave
through the disbelief door
and go home now.
Right. Sister Barnes?
Sister?
(WATER POURING)
Sister Barnes?
I think we should listen
to our super neat
and thoughtful host
and choose the right door?
You know. choose the "right"?
Like they taught us
in primary?
It doesn't...
matter what you say to him.
He's not gonna let us go
just because
we admit he's right.
Let's just get out of here
while our host is being
gracious enough
to let us leave.
(WHISPERING) I think that
we're being studied.
I think he wants to learn
something about us
based on which door we open.
Is that the game?
Someone scratches their neck.
and he's watching.
We say the wrong thing.
and he stumbles on his words.
A candle flame flickers.
and it captures his attention.
What have you
been looking for?
What have you found?
If I'm right.
then the only thing
that matters right now
is what we actually believe.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
And because I think
your rhetoric is thin.
and your garage sale
board game metaphor
is kind of offensive.
I mean. you asked
why Judaism only makes up
0.2% of the world's population
but didn't even pause
for the Holocaust.
You make no acknowledgement
of the religious persecution
Jewish people have faced.
You just use it as a setup
to a punchline
about missionaries.
And then.
you skip over the fact
that none of this
addresses Islam.
as Muslims don't even believe
Christ was resurrected.
And then. you point out
all the similarities
these mythological gods
have with Jesus.
but breeze over the many
glaring differences!
One of these guys
has a freaking bird head!
I don't think...
that my point of view...
fits into belief or disbelief.
I think there's
an entire spectrum
that your game is neglecting.
So it doesn't matter
what I believe. does it?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Sister Paxton. do you still
believe in God?
Yes.
Then let's leave through here.
Let's be honest and sincere
and let God decide
what happens next for us.
(PAXTON BREATHING HEAVILY)
(DOOR OPENS AND CREAKS)
Okay. we're leaving now.
Thank you
for all your mentorship.
and thank you
for letting us leave.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
Are you coming too?
(DOOR CREAKING)
(DOOR SHUTS)
(DOOR LOCKS)
PAXTON: Sister...
(CLICK)
BARNES: It's okay.
One step at a time.
We'll go slow.
(BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY)
(LOCK CLICKS)
(BOTH PANTING)
(RAPID BREATHING)
(BARNES WHIMPERS)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(WATER DRIPPING)
(LOCK CLATTERING)
PAXTON: Sister Barnes.
there's nothing.
It's all blocked off.
What do you think he wants?
Is he gonna
keep us here forever?
BARNES: No. he's too smart.
He...
He knows an Elder
will check on us. and...
which means he'll either have
to let us go or...
kill us.
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
From now on. if he lands
a philosophical point
that we don't agree with.
we challenge him.
We make him think.
He doesn't have
to steam roll us.
We might not
be a physical threat.
but we can
be an intellectual one.
(CHAIR CREAKING)
(GRUNTS)
- (CLATTERING)
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTS)
I think that window
has a cage on it.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
You're right.
(DOOR CREAKS)
BARNES: He's coming.
He's coming.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Take this.
Take this. Put it back.
If anything happens.
you take this.
and you stab him
in the neck as hard
and as fast as you can.
- No! No. no!
- It has to be you.
He's watching me too closely.
- He won't expect us to do it.
- Sister. no!
Okay. Let's have a code word.
Okay? Um...
Hey. if I say
"magic underwear."
that means stab. Okay?
(DISTANT THUD)
He's coming.
Magic underwear.
That's the code word. Okay?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CREAKING)
(PAXTON WHIMPERS)
(DOOR UNLOCKS)
(DOOR OPENS)
(CREAKING)
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
- (OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
- (BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY)
Mr. Reed?
(OMINOUS MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
(SQUELCHY FOOTSTEPS)
(LANTERN CREAKING)
- (WHIMPERS)
- Mrs. Reed?
Is that you?
(OMINOUS MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
(PAXTON WHIMPERING)
(BARNES INHALES SHARPLY)
(PAXTON GASPS)
(BONES CRACKING)
What's happening to her?
(RATTLE)
(CREEP BY RADIOHEAD PLAYING)
(MR. REED MOCKINGLY SINGING)
♪ But I'm a creep ♪
♪ I'm a weirdo ♪
(MR. REED LAUGHING)
BARNES: Mr. Reed?
BARNES: Where are you?
- (BARNES BREATHING HEAVILY)
- (MR. REED HUMS ALONG)
♪ Couldn't look you
in the eye ♪
♪ You're just like an angel ♪
(FIRE CRACKLING)
♪ Your skin makes me cry ♪
(SCRAPING)
(GROANING. WHEEZING)
(SHUSHES)
(MOUTHING IMPERCEPTIBLY)
(WHIMPERING SOFTLY)
(MOUTHING) No.
(OBJECTS CLANKING IN DISTANCE)
♪ And I'm a creep ♪
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(WOMAN WHISPERING
INDISTINCTLY)
(PANTING)
- (MR. REED HUMMING)
- (CREEP CONTINUES PLAYING)
(PANTING)
(RATTLING)
♪ I wanna have control ♪
♪ I want a perfect body ♪
(SCRAPING)
(SCRAPING.
THUDDING BEHIND DOOR)
♪ I want a perfect soul ♪
♪ I want you to notice ♪
♪ When I'm not around ♪
(LOUD BANGING)
♪ You're so very special ♪
♪ But I'm a creep ♪
♪ I'm a weirdo ♪
♪ What the hell
am I doin' here? ♪
♪ I don't belong here ♪
- (TAPE PLAYER SCREECHES)
- (CREEP STOPS PLAYING)
MR. REED OVER SPEAKERS:
I had to be sure
before I introduced you
to her.
Sure about what?
(BREATH TREMBLING)
You are now in the presence
of a living prophet of God.
(WOMAN WHISPERING
INDISTINCTLY)
- (WOMAN WHEEZING)
- (BONES CRACKING)
MR. REED: The reason
I invited you
into my sanctuary tonight
is because
I have been shown a miracle.
I believe
this miracle is proof
that all known religions
are demonstrably false.
and only an ancient echo
of something true.
I need a witness.
you. to verify
that the miracle is real.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
Now. our family recipe
for blueberry pie is.
I think. a traditional one.
The ingredients include
butter. flour. corn starch.
sugar. lemon.
blueberries. of course.
but tonight I've also included
some wolf's bane
and some belladonna.
which means that.
in a short while.
the Prophet will be dead
from consuming the pie.
(SQUELCHING)
MR. REED OVER SPEAKERS:
Then.
you will witness a miracle.
By the grace of God.
she will be resurrected.
(WHEEZING WEAKLY)
(CONTINUES WHEEZING WEAKLY)
- (RETCHES)
- (LANTERN CLATTERS)
Now. feel her pulse. please.
Both of you.
(WATER DRIPPING)
MR. REED OVER SPEAKERS:
I need you
to feel her pulse right now!
(PAXTON BREATHING HEAVILY)
MR. REED OVER SPEAKERS:
Acknowledge. please.
that her heart has now
stopped pumping.
Do you know how to do that?
Index and middle finger
on the side of the neck.
in the soft. hollow area
just beside the windpipe.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
MR. REED: Both of you. please.
lift her head to be sure.
(SQUELCHING)
(PAXTON SHUDDERS)
- (PROPHET GURGLES)
- (PAXTON GASPS)
PAXTON: She moved! She moved!
MR. REED: (LAUGHING) That was
just a catalytic spasm.
PAXTON: (GASPS) She's alive!
MR. REED: No! No. no. Not yet.
Chemicals being released
into her body.
Acknowledge. please.
that there's no pulse.
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
Acknowledge!
- No. No pulse.
- No pulse.
MR. REED: Thank you.
Acknowledge that she is
no longer breathing.
Do you feel a breath?
BARNES: No. No.
MR. REED: So she's dead.
BARNES: Yes.
- (WHIMPERS)
- MR. REED: Okay.
Thank you.
A moment longer. and you will
witness a resurrection.
She'll return
and she will tell us
what she saw in the afterlife.
Has the Prophet moved?
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
No.
MR. REED OVER SPEAKERS:
Hello?
- No. No.
- Mmm-mmm.
(BARNES WHIMPERS)
MR. REED: All right.
Just un momentino.
Only a moment longer.
- (BELL RINGING)
- (GASPS)
(BREATHING RAPIDLY)
The Elders?
(DOORBELL RINGS)
(FOOTSTEPS ECHOING)
(DOOR LOCKS)
- (TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
- (BOTH PANTING)
(PANTING)
- We scream.
BARNES: But not until
he answers the door.
(KNOCKING)
PAXTON: He's coming back.
BARNES: Scream! Scream!
(PAXTON AND BARNES SCREAMING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
- (DOOR SHUTS)
- (BOTH CONTINUE SCREAMING)
(LIGHTS CLICK)
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
(KNOCKING)
Coming!
(TICKING)
Ah! Sorry!
I was at the back. (CHUCKLES)
- No. I'm sorry to bother you.
- No.
I'm just in the neighborhood
looking for
two young ladies
from my church.
Oh.
Is everything all right?
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(BOTH PANTING)
They can't hear us.
MAN: I'm sure
everything's fine.
I was just wondering
if they...
(WIND BLOWING)
...stopped by.
No. I'm sorry to say.
you are the first house caller
I've had all day. so.
- Did you see this?
- It's locked.
BARNES: Help.
Help.
We can pull the rug.
The matches.
We start a fire.
smoke out the speaking pipe
to make sure
the Elder knows we're here.
Okay. But you did ask
for more information
on the church. correct?
Uh. this...
this is the which church?
The Church of Jesus Christ
of Latter-day Saints.
Yes. yes. yes. yes.
(WIND BLOWING)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
BARNES: Pull. Careful.
Is there some other way
I can help?
Do you want to use my phone.
call the police?
- I could get my coat...
- No. no. That's fine.
...and come help you
look around.
No. no. no. no. no.
I'm sure they're not far.
Uh. thank you for your time.
All right. well. good luck.
Yeah. I mean that.
- Okay.
- Uh-huh.
(WIND BLOWING)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
- (MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
- (DOOR CREAKS)
(CREAKING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(CLICKS)
(WATER POURING)
(THUD)
(FURNITURE DRAGGING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(CLICKING)
(SCRAPING)
- (FLOOR CREAKING)
- (FOOTSTEPS)
(MR. REED COUGHS)
(MR. REED CLEARS THROAT)
(OBJECT DRAGS)
(TENSE MUSIC BUILDS)
No.
(CLICKING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(BARNES BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BARNES GRUNTS)
- (THUD)
- (DOOR CREAKS)
PAXTON: (WHISPERING)
He's coming!
- (FOOTSTEPS)
- (SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOORBELL RINGS)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(RATTLING)
Yeah? Yeah? Any luck?
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(GASPS)
She moved.
- What do you mean?
- When we were gone.
No.
you're remembering it wrong.
She hasn't moved at all.
Her head is different.
- That's where she was!
- It's not!
Sister. that's not
how I remember it. Please!
Please. just come on! Help!
Hold the sleeve up.
I'd be remiss if I didn't
ask you one question.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC BUILDS)
(MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
Have you received
this booklet?
I have not.
but I will give it a look-see.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
PAXTON: Try another.
BARNES: I know.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Focus.
(WIND BLOWING)
(RATTLING)
Faster.
(MATCH IGNITES)
(BARNES WHIMPERS)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC BUILDS)
(GASPS)
(BARNES GRUNTS)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
(MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
(WIND GUSTING)
(MATCH SCRAPING ON WALL)
(BARNES WHIMPERS)
(BARNES BREATHING HEAVILY)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(MATCH IGNITES)
- (SCREAMS)
- (GASPS)
- (BOTH GASPING)
- (WHEEZES)
- (RETCHES)
- (BOTH GASPING)
(RETCHES)
(COUGHS)
(PROPHET WHEEZES)
PROPHET: Conductor...
says... my... name.
White... clouds.
Not... Heaven.
They... unplug...
my brain.
It is...
not...
real.
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
MR. REED:
And. thank you. Prophet.
We are very grateful
for your passage
to the other side.
(WHEEZING)
Your prophecy will be recorded
into our liturgical texts.
Come. You must be exhausted.
Take my arm.
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(BARNES BREATHING HEAVILY)
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(DOOR UNLOCKS)
(MATCH SCRAPING)
(PROPHET WHIMPERS)
(DOOR CREAKS. SHUTS)
Well. now.
You see. this is rather
interesting because...
- (OBJECT CLANKS)
- (MR. REED CHUCKLES)
I know that one of you
has been lying
since you first got here.
(CHUCKLING)
And do you know
how I know that?
Excuse me. can I...
can I take that?
I know from the way
that the fire reacts
to each of you.
A.
B.
Yeah. One of you has
a very. very... (CHUCKLING)
...very big secret.
but we will know more soon.
There will be
before you saw a woman die
and come back to life.
and there will be after.
(BLOWS) Books will be written
about it.
So choose your words
very carefully when I ask.
what did you witness?
Tell me. Tell me what you saw.
How did she...
I don't know...
And if you didn't
see something transcendental.
you absolutely must tell me.
I don't know.
'Cause if I'm wrong.
I need to hear it.
That's why you're here.
It's a contrived experiment.
We are your prisoners!
- It doesn't make sense...
- MR. REED: Oh. pooh!
- We're all prisoners together.
- ...for us to have an opinion!
You must know by now
that any of us can leave
whenever we want.
but why would we want.
after what we've seen?
I saw it. I saw it.
I heard her describe
what she experienced
on the other side.
Great! What did you hear?
She said
there was a conductor.
- Yes. Yeah.
- Did she mean angel?
She had a feeling
of disassociation.
a feeling that something
wasn't real.
That's it.
So now you know.
Now. we know?
Yeah. now. you know.
Know?
I can show you God.
If you're willing to die.
It... it can be painless.
It can be temporary.
Like the Prophet.
you can be brought back.
It doesn't have
to be frightening at all.
I'll tell you... I'll tell you
what's frightening.
Not knowing is frightening!
Where do we come from?
What are we doing here?
What's our purpose?
The terror of those questions
is why religions exist.
I can answer
those questions for you.
I can give you a comfort
no religion in the world
is capable of giving you.
It all makes sense now.
I've been asking myself
all night.
how is he gonna
make killing us our idea?
(MR. REED SIGHS)
Sister Barnes.
you're in a muddle.
I know. I can't tell
if you're playing chess
or checkers.
Monopoly!
Come on. it was right there.
You didn't show us a miracle.
Okay. what did I show you?
That wasn't a miracle.
MR. REED: So you say.
What did I show you?
That was not a miracle!
It was a magic trick.
MR. REED: A magic trick?
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
You wanna know why
we don't talk about Taco Bell?
It killed me
when I was four years old.
Fifty people were hospitalized
from an E. coli outbreak.
The kids at school
called me Taco Hell
'cause I was clinically dead
while doctors operated
on my kidneys.
When I was dead.
I saw exactly
what your prophet described.
A blinding white light.
clouds. but not Heaven.
a sense of wanting to return.
a feeling that my state
of reality wasn't real.
That wasn't a prophecy.
That was a near-death
experience.
When the oxygen
leaves your brain
or your heart stops pumping.
your mind
creates unbelievable things.
I think you've been
keeping this woman
on the edge of death
in order to ask her questions
about meaningless
hallucinations
so that you can substantiate
your idea
of what the one.
true religion really is.
MR. REED: Did you know...
that when you remember
something.
you're really only remembering
the last time you remembered
that experience?
You're not actually
recalling the event.
So your memory of dying
at Taco Bell... (CHUCKLING)
...isn't really of dying.
it's of the memory
of the memory
of the memory of the memory...
stop me... (CHUCKLES)
...of that event.
So you're remembering
a false correlation
with the experience
you've just witnessed.
But this.
this is happening right now!
That's why I think.
Sister Barnes. Sister Paxton.
that you really need
to pay attention
because I promise you...
(CHUCKLING)
...we're not talking
about a magic trick.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
No.
we're talking
about magic underwear...
- (SLASHING)
- (MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(INAUDIBLE SCREAMING)
(IMPERCEPTIBLE)
(SCREAMING) Help me! Help!
(WIND GUSTING)
(SOBS)
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(SIGHS)
(EXHALES SHAKILY)
MR. REED:
She'll come back to us!
I promise!
Sister Paxton.
do not be scared!
She will rise again.
Challenge him.
Debate.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(FOOTSTEPS)
MR. REED: Come on. now.
Sister B.
Wakey-wakey!
- (WATER DRIPPING)
- Whoa. whoa. whoa.
whoa. whoa. whoa!
No. that's not it.
That's not it.
That's a... a mucky pup.
Let's have that.
(CHUCKLES)
Moments. It'll be moments.
Let's have one
of your drum rolls. yeah?
Whoop!
Hey! (SNIFFLES)
I'm very sorry.
Something is wrong.
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
I'm now worried...
that she's not...
(BOX CUTTER OPENS)
...coming back to us.
Yeah.
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
Oh. yeah.
- (SOBS)
- MR. REED: Oh. yeah.
Yep.
Yeah.
There it is.
(GRUNTS)
No. it isn't.
That was a vein.
(MR. REED GRUNTS)
(SQUELCHING)
A-ha! (CHUCKLES) A-ha.
(TENSE MUSIC BUILDS)
The implant.
This is why she can't
come back to us.
Take a look!
I'm very sorry.
But Sister Barnes.
she's a program.
She's not real.
Do you know what gave it away?
The candles.
What are you saying?
I don't understand.
No. no. I know.
I know. I know.
How could you?
(SHUDDERS)
Can you explain it to me?
Are you. Sister Paxton.
familiar with
the Daoist concept
of "The Butterfly Dream"?
PAXTON: A butterfly...
A butterfly flaps its wings
and causes a typhoon?
That is
"The Butterfly Effect."
Common mistake. No.
"The Butterfly Dream"...
(CLATTERING)
...concerns an ancient
Chinese philosopher
who asked himself
the following question.
- (OBJECT CLATTERS)
- "Was I a man dreaming
"I'm a butterfly.
or am I now..."
(THUD)
"...a butterfly dreaming
that I am a man?"
Come and sit down.
Come on.
(CLICKS TONGUE) Here.
(SIGHS)
(SCRAPING ON TABLE)
This is us.
You and me alone together.
That was Barnes.
Bye-bye. Barnes.
I have come
to a dark realization
that we exist inside
a simulation so advanced
that we cannot tell the
difference between real life
and artificial dream.
You heard the Prophet.
She said. "It is not real."
You see. fire dynamics
are very difficult to render.
I've noticed this anomaly
in its behavior
when it interacts
with simulated NPCs.
like poor old Sister B.
She couldn't come back to us.
but when you die.
finger. please.
you will pass through death
- and wake up...
- (BOX CUTTER RATTLES)
...into the real world.
What do you think?
Yes. no. maybe?
Um...
That's a theory.
Well yeah.
you're very welcome to...
to challenge my premise.
I love that.
- (BOX CUTTER CLOSES)
- Go for it.
(SNIFFLING)
I don't think
this is a microchip.
MR. REED: Oh?
I think it's a contraceptive.
A... a birth control implant.
Huh.
Tell me. have you ever met
a Mormon missionary
who was on birth control?
Did "Sister Barnes" say
she was on birth control?
PAXTON: Our church
would've made her
feel ashamed about it.
and she would've been
too embarrassed.
- Simulation theory is...
- Ah!
"Hypothesis." please.
Sorry. it doesn't matter.
Simulation hypothesis
is not testable. is it?
No. it's a matter of belief.
like any religion.
You either believe it.
green door.
or you don't believe it.
purple door.
With all due respect.
I...
I don't believe it.
I'm not smart enough
to say why. I just don't.
Do you believe the miracle
that I showed you?
PAXTON: Yes.
- Yeah?
- PAXTON: At first.
But now?
I think something
happened tonight
that you didn't expect.
It feels like
you're improvising.
trying to convince me
of a simulation theory
that's not sticking.
Am I right?
Uh. (CHUCKLES) are you
asking me if you're right
that I am improvising
or you're right
that the simulation narrative
is not sticking?
- Yes.
- (TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
High-five.
(GRUNTS SOFTLY. CHUCKLES)
So. in fact.
you agree with your friend.
You think that the Prophet
was just hallucinating
a meaningless.
near-death experience.
No.
I think you switched
the bodies.
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
I just haven't
figured out how yet.
I switched...
the bodies?
(FIRE CRACKLING)
The doorbell rang
when the Elder got here.
- (TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
- (DOORBELL RINGING)
Which drew our attention
to the stairs.
You would have been
prepared for that.
When we came back downstairs.
I noticed the woman wasn't in
the same position as before.
It was similar...
PAXTON: Her head is different.
But it was not the exact same.
I think another woman
who looked exactly like her
came into the basement
through a hidden door
or something.
disposed of her body and then
took her place at the table.
I see.
And then.
once we got back downstairs.
she read off
a scripted prophecy
that you prepared for her.
Except the last thing
she said was.
"It is not real."
...not... real...
Maybe she was trying
to tell us
that the miracle wasn't real.
Ah.
You see what I mean when I say
something happened
that you didn't expect?
I think you gave her a script.
and she went off the book.
and now you're
trying to recover.
Well. if that's right.
then. uh.
there'd have to be another way
into this basement. yeah?
Shall we have a look?
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
I don't think there is.
No.
I'm not doing very well.
Sister Paxton.
Unless...
(WATER DRIPPING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(RATTLING)
(WATER POURING)
(WATER DRAINING)
- (CLANKING)
- (MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
(CREAKING)
Which means that...
there would have to be
a dead body down there
if you were right. huh?
PAXTON: Correct.
MR. REED: How will you
test your theory?
(SIGHS) I don't know.
MR. REED: But will you go
into that hole and
see if there's
somebody down there?
If I have to.
MR. REED: Why would you
do that?
Because I want
to know the truth.
and because the only way out
is through.
Robert Frost?
Swamp Thing.
(CHUCKLES)
Don't go into that cellar...
unless you are prepared
to discover the one.
true religion.
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(SNIFFLES)
(LADDER CREAKS)
(RISING SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
- (MUSIC STOPS)
- (SIGHS)
(FOOTSTEPS)
I knew it.
(DOOR CREAKS AND SLAMS)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
- (WATER SPLASHING)
- (TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(LOCK CREAKS AND CLICKS)
(DOOR CREAKS)
(CONTINUES HEAVY BREATHING)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOOR CREAKS)
(SHARP INHALE)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(WATER DRIPPING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CONTINUES HEAVY BREATHING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(GASPS)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(CLANK)
(DISTANT WEAK WHEEZING)
(SHUDDERING BREATH)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(COUGHING)
(FAINT GROANING)
(SHIVERING BREATH)
Hey.
(SNIFFLES)
(PAXTON SHIVERING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Sorry about the cold.
(SNIFFLES)
Have you figured it out yet?
(PAXTON SNIFFLES)
I think so.
MR. REED: So what is it?
What is the one.
true religion. Sister P?
(PAXTON SHIVERING)
(SNIFFLING)
It's...
(INHALES)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
When we first arrived.
you left us alone
in your living room.
(DRAMATIC. SUSPENSEFUL
MUSIC PLAYING)
We thought you were talking
to your wife.
but you were doing
something else.
I was.
PAXTON: You took a key
from Sister Barnes' coat.
went outside to unlock
our bikes and hide them.
I noticed your hair was wet
when you came back
with the drinks. like you were
out in the storm.
You did this. I assume.
because you didn't want
the Elder to find our bikes
when he came back
looking for us.
(LATCH CLANKS)
But there was something else
on your mind.
(WATER POURING)
- There was.
- (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
PAXTON: You returned
the bike key
to the wrong coat pocket.
We thought this was a mistake
you made.
(MOUTHING) Key.
PAXTON: (VOICE SHAKING)
But now I know it wasn't.
Why?
(INHALES)
You gave the bike lock
to one of your prophets.
instructed them to lock
the final cellar door with it.
But why. why. why?
Why did I do that?
Because you wanted me to know
the only reason
I'm standing here right now
is because it is exactly
where you want me
to be standing.
I'm not here
because I chose to be.
I'm here because you made me
choose to be.
Oh.
Because you want me to believe
the one. true religion is...
(SIGHS)
...control.
(CHUCKLES)
That is exactly right.
Religion is just
a system of control...
(WHEEZING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
It's okay.
I'll help you.
MR. REED: No. you see.
that's what's so interesting.
They don't want your help.
They... (CHUCKLING)
they are exactly
where they chose to be.
But you killed that woman.
MR. REED: I disagree.
She... She chose to eat
a poisoned pie
because of her profound faith.
It is called drinking the...
anyone?
(SNAPPING SHEARS)
Kool-Aid.
It is true...
that I keep these ladies
a little chilly.
and a little peckish.
for which I am very sorry.
Sorry. ladies.
But only for the same reason
that your church goes to Haiti
to give out Bibles
after a hurricane.
It's easier to control
- someone who has lost...
- (SHEARS CLICK)
- ...everything.
You're absolutely right.
She did go off-book.
- (SHEARS SLICE)
- (PROPHET SCREAMS)
Why do you do this?
The question is.
why do you all let me?
(SPLASH)
(WHIMPERING)
(WHEEZING)
PAXTON: Sorry... (CRYING)
You are here
because the ideas of others
have influenced every single
decision you've made
since the day you were born.
and I've been able to predict
every decision you would make
tonight because of that.
(WHIMPERING)
- (CRYING)
- (SHUSHING)
You have allowed them
to dictate
every decision of your life.
(CRYING)
They decide who you worship.
where you worship.
what you worship.
- (PAXTON BREATHING HEAVILY)
- (SPRINKLER SPRAYING)
They even dictate the garments
you wear under your clothes.
The what?
Your magic underwear.
- (SLASHING)
- (MR. REED SCREAMS. GURGLES)
- (SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
- (PAXTON PANTING)
(GROANING)
(SQUELCHING)
(PANTING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(OMINOUS MUSIC BUILDS)
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
(PANTING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
No... No...
No...
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(SQUELCHING)
(GASPS)
(PAXTON WHIMPERS)
(CLATTER)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(PAXTON WHIMPERING)
- (DOOR SLAMMING SHUT)
- (PAXTON GASPS)
- (PANTING)
- (MR. REED GROANING)
(WHEEZING)
(GROANS)
(LAUGHS)
(PAXTON WHIMPERING)
(GROANING)
(EXHALES HEAVILY)
(GROANS. INHALES SHARPLY)
MR. REED: (WEAKLY) Pray...
(WHIMPERS)
Pray.
(WATER DRIPPING)
(WHIMPERS)
Pray for us.
(EXHALES)
Praying... (INHALES SHARPLY)
...doesn't work.
(BREATHING WEAKLY)
(PAINED BREATH)
(PAXTON PANTING)
Have you ever heard of
the great prayer experiment?
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
They divided patients
into groups.
Those who received prayers
and those who didn't.
The results of the study
were conclusive.
It doesn't work.
But I think it's beautiful
that we all pray
for each other...
(MR. REED GROANS)
...even though
we all probably know
it doesn't make a difference.
(WHEEZING)
It's just nice to think about
someone other than yourself.
Even if it's you.
(GROANS)
(BREATHING WEAKLY)
- (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
- (PAXTON PRAYING INDISTINCTLY)
...I'm grateful
for all the trials
you've given me in my life.
And for your path
that you've laid out for me.
(WHEEZING) Quietly.
(MR. REED WHIMPERS)
(MR. REED WHEEZES)
(PAXTON CONTINUES
PRAYING INDISTINCTLY)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT PRAYER)
- (MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
- (SLASHING)
- (MR. REED GROANS. SCREAMS)
- (GASPS)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
(SLOW. DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
YAWNTiC Encode | www.movieddl.me
(SOMBER INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
(IMPERCEPTIBLE)
(WATER DROPS PATTERING)
Goodbye. Sister.
(SNIFFLES)
(KISSES)
(SOBBING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(PANTING)
(WHIMPERS)
(CONTINUES PANTING)
(CREAKING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(PANTING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC RISES)
(MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
(WIND BLOWING)
(KNOCKING ON HEAVEN'S DOOR
BY SOPHIE THATCHER PLAYING)
♪ Mama take this badge
off me ♪
♪ I can't use it anymore ♪
♪ It's getting dark
too dark to see ♪
♪ I feel like I'm knockin' on
Heaven's door ♪
♪ Knock-knock-knockin'
on Heaven's door ♪
♪ Mama put my guns
in the ground ♪
♪ I can't shoot them anymore ♪
♪ That long black cloud
is comin' down ♪
♪ Feels like I'm knockin' on
Heaven's door ♪
♪ Knock-knock-knockin'
on Heaven's door ♪
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org